Register of the Maciej Józef Kwiatkowski papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Maciej Józef Kwiatkowski papers
1944-1992
92050
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Writings and radio broadcast transcripts relating to the history of radio broadcasting in Poland, and especially to use of radio broadcasting by the Polish resistance movement during World War II. Includes copies of transcripts of radio broadcasts from Warsaw by the Polish resistance during the Warsaw uprising of 1944.
Kwiatkowski, Maciej Józef.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1992.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Maciej Józef Kwiatkowski (1920-1994) was a historian of Polish radio. He participated in the Warsaw Uprising in 1944 and worked in Polish radio before becoming a professor of history focusing on mass media in Poland in the twentieth century.
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings and radio broadcast transcripts relating to the history of radio broadcasting in Poland, and especially to use of radio broadcasting by the Polish resistance movement during World War II.
The collection is about essentially one subject: Polish radio and the Warsaw Uprising. The first part contains transcripts of English and Polish radio broadcasts by the resistance during the uprising. The second part includes manuscripts of Kwiatkowski's own publications about Polish radio and the uprising.
Radio broadcasting--Poland.; Polskie Radio.; World War, 1939-1945--Underground movements.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.; Poland--History--Occupation, 1939-1945.; Warsaw (Poland)--History--Uprising, 1944.
- Polish Radio Transcripts, 1944
  - August 9-12 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - August 14-19 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - August 20-23 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - August 24-26 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - August 27-31 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - September 1, 9 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - September 11-15 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - September 16-21 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - September 22-October 2 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Months and days unknown (Box-folder 1: 10)
- Writings, 1980-1992
  - „Tu mówi powstańcza Warszawa" manuscript, 1991
    - Front matter (Box-folder 1: 11)
    - Akt I (Box-folder 1: 12)
    - Akt II (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - Akt III (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - Akt IV (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - Final (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - „Tu polskie radio Warszawa...": rozwój i społeczno-polityczna rola radiofonii w Warszawie w latach 1918-1939 manuscript, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous writings, 1992 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    Scope and Contents note
    Description of his book manuscript, „Tu mówi powstańcza Warszawa" in English and Polish; transcript of eight-page talk, in Polish, delivered in 1992, „Witaj majowa jurzenko: w 201 rocznicę Konstytucji 3 Maja."